(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-27T04:20:54.130539",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ぅん……
Hmmm...
また迷った？
Am I lost again?
このドア、なんか怪しげ……
This door looks sus.
入る？
Should I?
それともやめとく？
Or should I not?
まあ、いっか。
Oh well.
Dahlah saja
Walk it off and go
Isn't this a thing that you're used to?
Disappointed and feeling blue
When the world doesn't go the way you want it to, oh, oh
And maybe now is just the perfect time
To let it go and just unwind
There's no need to ask why ever again
Just let it go, the answer you've been looking for
No need to be sad about it, just try to get through your day
Just let it go
Then maybe in the end you'll know you got what it takes to get through the ache and still win the day
Dahlah saja, oh, dahlah saja
Walk it off and go
What else can you do?
When your feelings are barely there
Up to a point of pure despair
When you have given it your all, but ends in vain
Just let it go, the answer you've been looking for
No need to be sad about it, just try to get through your day
Just let it go
Then maybe in the end you'll know you got what it takes to get through the ache and still win the day
Let life take over the wheel
And shift it to higher gears
Then you will finally see
Just let it go
The answer you've been looking for
You don't need to be sad
You don't need to be mad
Just try to get through your day
Just let it go
Then maybe in the end you'll know
You got what it takes to get through the ache
And still win the day
Dahlah saja, oh, dahlah saja
Let it go, oh, let it go
Walk it off and go
Dahlah saja, oh, dahlah saja
Let it go, oh, let it go
Walk it off and go
Maa ii ka
Well, whatever
Podcast sendiri, ya?
ソロポッドキャストってこと？
Doing a podcast by yourself?
Kaelooo~!
カエロオオオ～！
Nani?
なに？
What?
Apaan, tuh?
なにこれ？
What's that?
Hmm...
うーん……
9 lampu...
9つのライトがある……
9 lights...
Mic...
マイク……
headset...
ヘッドセット……
Headset...
Content creator?
まさかコンテンツクリエイター……？
Eh?
え……
The color...
その色……？
hololive ID!?
ホロライブID!?
Sahabat sejatiku, hilangkah dari ingatanmu
My true friend, have you vanished from my memory?
Di hari kita saling berbaginya
On the days we shared with each other
Dengan kotak sejuta mimpi
With a box of a million dreams
Aku datang menghampirimu,
I come to approach you,
kuperlihatkan semua hartaku
I show you all my treasures
Kita selalu berpendapat,
We always think
kita ini yang terhebat
that we are the greatest
Kesombongan di masa muda yang indah
The arrogance of a beautiful youth
Aku raja kau pun raja
I am a king, you are a king too
Aku hitam kau pun hitam
I am black, you are black too
Arti teman lebih dari sekadar materi
Friendship means more than just material
Pegang pundakku jangan pernah lepaskan
Hold my shoulder, never let go
Bila ku mulai lelah, lelah dan tak bersinar
When I start to get tired, tired and not shining
Remas sayapku jangan pernah lepaskan
Squeeze my wings, never let go
Bila ku ingin terbang
When I want to fly
Terbang meninggalkanmu
Flying away leaving you
Ku selalu membanggakanmu,
I always boast about you,
kau pun selalu menyanjungku
you always praise me
Aku dan kamu darah abadi
You and I are eternal blood
Demi bermain bersama
For the sake of playing together
Kita duakan segalanya
We share everything in two
Merdeka kita kita merdeka
We are free, we are free
Pegang pundakku jangan pernah lepaskan
Hold my shoulder, never let go
Bila ku mulai lelah, lelah dan tak bersinar
When I start to get tired, tired and not shining
Remas sayapku jangan pernah lepaskan
Squeeze my wings, never let go
Bila ku ingin terbang
When I want to fly
Terbang meninggalkanmu
Flying away leaving you
Tak pernah kita pikirkan ujung perjalanan ini
We never thought about the end of this journey
Tak usah kita pikirkan ujung perjalanan ini
No need to think about the end of this journey
Dan tak usah kita pikirkan ujung perjalanan ini
And no need to think about the end of this journey
Happy anniversary! Dahlah!
Okay, that's kinda an easy trick.
Okay, that's kind of an easy trick.
So that's how these rooms work, huh?
I guess this door is locked too, right?
Okay.
I need to find a clue here and get out. Hmm...
OPEN THIS
ONLY FOR THE WEAK ONES
What am I supposed to do with this?
Coffee? Arrow? Right? What?
There's another box, but I'm not the weak one, so...
I have no idea.
Who's gonna judge me anyway if I...
I just need to get out from here and leave this weird place or else I'll be late for my 3D showcase...
Langkah, jalan kiri.
Step, walk left.
Oke, ya dah sana.
Okay, go over there.
Satu, dua, tiga, loncat, jalan, kiri.
One, two, three, jump, walk, left.
Loncat, jalan, kanan. Jangan pula-pula lompat.
Jump, walk, right. Don't randomly jump.
Loncat, kiri lagi. Loncat.
Jump, left again. Jump.
Ini yang penting bisa ya.
The important thing is we can do this.
Kiri, gerak, gerak, gerak!
Left, move, move, move!
Eh? I don't get it.
Huh? I don't get it.
Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa! Kopi Kannon?!
Ya ampun...
Oh my goodness...
What kind of clue is that?
Mentari terbenam
The sun sets,
temani dalam kesendirianku
accompanying me in my solitude.
Temani aku dalam kepedihan ini
Accompany me in this sorrow,
Ini ku bertahan
here I endure.
Mentari terbenam
The sun sets,
beri semangat baru tuk jiwaku
giving new spirit to my soul.
Beri kicauan merdu tuk hidupku ini
Give a sweet chirp to this life of mine,
Ini ku bertahan
here I endure.
Aku pasti bisa
I know I can do it,
Menikmati semua dan menghadapinya
enjoying everything and facing it all.
Aku yakin pasti bisa
I'm sure I can do it.
Mentari terbenam
The sun sets,
beri semangat baru tuk jiwaku
giving new spirit to my soul.
Beri kicauan merdu tuk hidupku ini
Give a sweet chirp to this life of mine,
Ini ku bertahan
here I endure.
Aku pasti bisa
I know I can do it,
Menikmati semua dan menghadapinya
enjoying everything and facing it all.
Aku yakin pasti bisa
I'm sure I can do it.
Aku pasti bisa
I know I can do it,
Menikmati semua dan menghadapinya
enjoying everything and facing it all.
Aku yakin pasti bisa
I'm sure I can do it.
Aku ingin lepaskan seluruh bebanku
I want to release all my burdens,
Dan ku jalani hidupku dengan senyuman
and live my life with a smile.
bukannya sudah biasa?
Isn't it usual?
ditikam oleh kecewa
Stabbed by disappointment,
saat dunia tak berjalan semestinya (oh, oh)
when the world doesn't go as it should (oh, oh).
mungkin sudahlah saatnya
Maybe it's time
kau coba lepaskan saja
you try to let it go.
tak perlu tanya mengapa lagi
No need to ask why again.
jika memang...
If indeed...
jawaban tak kau dapatkan
you don't get the answer,
jangan tangisi
don't cry.
coba lalui teka-tekinya
Try to go through the puzzle.
relakan lah
Let it go,
karena pada akhirnya
because in the end,
kau lebih kuat daripada yang kau kira
you are stronger than you thought.
Oh...
ruangannya kok...
This room is...
beda, ya?
different?
Hah?
Huh?
Tidur.
Sleeping.
Emang dia tahu kalau aku bohong?
Does this thing know if I lie?
Bodo amat, ah... tidur.
Whatever, sleeping.
Jangan nanya hal yang sama terus, dong!
Stop asking me the same question!
Hobiku tidur, aku suka tidur.
Sleeping, I love sleeping.
Ini bercanda, ya?
Is this some kind of joke?
Hobiku itu nggak jawab pertanyaan yang sama terus-terusan.
My hobby is anything except answering the same questions over and over again.
Hadeh, bisa nggak sih buka aja pintunya? Udah cukup, ah.
Can the door just please open? I've had enough with this.
Nggak. Aku nggak mau jawab.
No. I refuse to answer.
Dahlah, mau, nggak.
Whatever.
Ohh!
Ohhh!
Akhirnya pertanyaannya beda! Gampang lagi!
Finally, a different one and an easy one, too!
8! Tentu aja 8! 8! 8! Di mana-mana, 8!
8! Of course, 8!
広い宇宙の 数ある一つ
In this wide universe, there is...
青い地球の 広い世界で
a big world in a blue earth.
小さな恋の 思いは届く
A small memory of love will reach
小さな島の人 あなたのもとへ
you who are living in a small island.
あなたと出会い 時は流れる
Time has passed since I met you.
思いを込めた 手紙もふえる
The letter with my piled-up feelings increases.
いつしか二人 お互いに響く
Without us realizing, it is already echoing between us.
時に激しく 時に切なく
Sometimes we're full of intensity, sometimes we're full of sadness.
響きは遠く 遥か彼方へ
These feelings echo distantly.
やさしい歌は 世界を変える
This gentle love song will change the world.
ほら あなたにとって大事な人ほど
Look, the person who is important to you
すぐそばにいるの
is right beside you.
ただ あなたにだけ届いて欲しい
I just want you to receive
響け恋の歌
this echoing love song.
ほら ほら ほら 響け恋の歌
Listen, listen, listen to this echoing love song.
あなたは気づく 二人は歩く
You've realized even when we walked
暗い道でも 日々照らす月
in the dark, the moonlight will shine on us.
握りしめた手 離すことなく
I won't let go of your hand.
思いは強く 永遠誓う
I swear that these strong feelings will last for eternity.
永遠のふち きっと僕は言う
In the depths of forever, I'll definitely say
思い変わらず 同じ言葉を
these same words without any change of feelings.
それでも足りず 涙に変わり
Even if it's still not enough, it'll change into tears,
喜びになり 言葉にできず
and it'll change into joy that I can't put into words.
ただ抱きしめる ただ抱きしめる
I'll just hold you, I'll just hold you.
ほら あなたにとって大事な人ほど
Look, the person who is important to you
すぐそばにいるの
is right beside you.
ただ あなたにだけ届いて欲しい
I just want you to receive
響け恋の歌
this echoing love song.
ほら ほら ほら 響け恋の歌
Listen, listen, listen to this echoing love song.
夢なら覚めないで 夢なら覚めないで
If it's a dream don't wake up, if it's a dream don't wake up.
あなたと過ごした時 永遠の星となる
The time I've spent with you will become an everlasting star.
ほら あなたにとって大事な人ほど
Look, the person who is important to you
すぐそばにいるの
is right beside you.
ただ あなたにだけ届いて欲しい
I just want you to receive
響け恋の歌
this echoing love song.
ほら あなたにとって大事な人ほど
Look, the person who is important to you
すぐそばにいるの
is right beside you.
ただ あなたにだけ届いて欲しい
I just want you to receive
響け恋の歌
this echoing love song.
ほら ほら ほら 響け恋の歌
Listen, listen, listen to this echoing love song.
響け 恋の歌 ほら
Ring out, song of love,
あなたにとって
for you,
大事な人ほど すぐそばにいるの
the most important person is right beside you.
ただ あなたにだけ 届いてほしい
I just want it to reach only you.
響け 恋の歌 ほら
Ring out, song of love, look...
ほら... 響け恋の歌
Look... Ring out, song of love.
え？何を繰り返すの？
Eh? What am I repeating?
カオス？
Chaos?
頭の中は確かにカオスだけど、どういうこと？
My mind is indeed chaotic, but what?
生徒の机が５つ、そして先生の机が１つ……
5 student desks and 1 teacher's desk...
分からないね。
I don't get it.
カオス。
Chaos.
え？
Eh?
ハコス・ベールズ？
Hakos Baelz?
もしかして、これ？
Could this be what I think?
ＪＤＯＮＮ ＭＹ ＳＯＵＬＬ！！
JDONN MY SOULL!!
なんで開かないの？
Why won't it open?
あっ、10回ってことか！
Ah, 10 times!
ＪＤＯＮＮ ＭＹ ＳＯＵＬＬ 10回ね！
JDONN MY SOULL 10 times!
いや、たぶんそうじゃない。
No, probably not like that.
ＪＤＯＮＮ ＭＹ ＳＯＵＬＬ...
JDONN MY SOULL...
wanna be the biggest dreamer
全速力で未来も今も駆け抜けろ
Running full speed through the future and present!
そう 僕は気づいたんだ ずっと宿題忘れてた
That's right, I realized I forgot my homework all along.
それは 一つの謎謎謎 「僕は誰なんだろう」
That's a puzzle, puzzle, puzzle: \"Who am I?\"
スライディングして擦りむいたヒザ 痛くたってさ
Even if I slide and skin my knees, even if it hurts,
big and bigger biggest dreamer
夢見ることがすべて始まりそれが答えだろ
Dreaming is the start of everything, that's the answer, right?
誰より遠くへ飛んで見せるよすべての明日を貫いて
I'll fly farther than anyone, piercing through all of tomorrow!
地平線まで飛んでいけ 羽をもらった勇気たち
Fly to the horizon, our courage has gained wings!
強くなるために 僕も走りだそう
In order to grow stronger, I'll run too!
聞こえてたよ カウントダウン ずっと前から
I've heard the countdown for a long time.
準備はできてきたさ 今すぐ始めよう ゼロに変われ
I'm prepared, let's start now, change into zero!
big and bigger biggest dreamer 信じられないきゃ 瞬きしてるセツナに消えるよ
Big and bigger biggest dreamer, if we can't believe, it disappears in a blink!
ココロの標的そらさず走れ すべてのチカラぶつけよう
Run straight for our heart's target, striking with all our power!
big and bigger biggest dreamer 夢見ることがすべて始まり それが答えだろ
Big and bigger biggest dreamer, dreaming is the start of everything!
wanna be the biggest dreamer 全速力で未来も今も駆け抜けろ
Wanna be the biggest dreamer, running full speed through the future and present!
wanna be the biggest dreamer
全速力で 未来も現在(いま)も 駆け抜けろ
Running full speed through the future and the present
そう僕は気付いたんだ
That's right, I've realized it
ずっと宿題忘れてた
I had forgotten my homework all along
それは一つの謎・謎・謎
That's a single puzzle, puzzle, puzzle
「僕は誰なんだろ？」
"Who could I be?"
スライディングして すりむいたヒザ
Sliding and scraping my knee
痛くたってね すぐ立ち上がらなきゃ
Even if it hurts, I've gotta stand right back up
チャンスは逃げてゆく 分かってるさ
Or my chance will run away, I know
big and bigger, biggest dreamer!
夢見るコトが すべてはじまり
Dreaming is the start of everything
それが答えだろ
That's the answer, right?
誰より遠くまで 飛んで見せるよ
I'll fly farther than anyone else
すべての明日を貫いて
Piercing through every tomorrow
地平線まで飛んでゆけ
Fly away to the horizon
羽をもらった勇気たち
The courage that was given wings
強く大きくなるために
To grow strong and big
僕も走りだそう
I'll start running too
聞こえていたよ カウントダウン
I could hear the countdown
ずっと前から 準備はできてるさ
I've been ready for a long time
今すぐ始めよう
Let's start right now
ゼロに変われ!
Change into zero!
big and bigger, biggest dreamer!
爆弾？！
A bomb?!
これはさすがにやりすぎでしょ。
This is getting out of hand already.
普通に3Dお披露目を するはずだったのに、何故か、閉じ込められて、爆弾まで出てきて……、で、ですね、モールス暗号まで解読しろって？
I was supposed to be doing my 3D showcase, but somehow I got locked in a room with a bomb and I need to decipher Morse code?
最悪すぎる一日なんだけど！！
What a terrible day!!
しかもスマホ？マジでどうすればいいの？YAGOOさんに電話して「迷子です。助けてください」って言えばいいの？
And a phone? What am I supposed to do? Call YAGOO and tell him "I'm lost, please help me"?
分かったかも！スマホを取り出して……
I think I know what to do! Taking out my phone...
も、もしもし？
H-Hello?
私、今迷って、閉じ込められて、爆弾もある。
I'm lost and trapped with a bomb.
え？
What?
モールス信号解読できなかったら、もう終わりだよ。
I hope you can solve Morse code or it's so over.
えぇ？
Huh?
オッケー。ダッシュドット、ダッシュダッシュ、ダッシュダッシュダッシュ、ダッシュドット、ダッシュドットダッシュダッシュ、ダッシュドット。
Okay. Dash dot, dash dash, dash dash dash, dash dot, dash dot dash dash, dash dot.
C、H、A……
C, H, A...
早い！もうすぐ爆発する！！
Fast! It's gonna explode!!
もう一回言って？
Can you repeat it again?
ダッシュドット、ダッシュダッシュダッシュ、ダッシュドット、ダッシュダッシュ、ダッシュダッシュ、ダッシュドット、ダッシュドットダッシュダッシュ、ダッシュドット。
Dash dot, dash dash dash, dash dot, dash dash, dash dash, dash dot, dash dot dash dash, dash dot.
M、O、N、うーん、CHAMONってなに？
M, O, N, um... what is CHAMON?
マジで死ぬかもー。
I think I'm gonna die.
続きはY、A……
The last one is Y, A...
CHAMONYA？何それ？
CHAMONYA? What?
よく分からないけど、がんばって！
I don't know what you're doing, but good luck!
ありがとう！バイバイン！
Thanks! Bye!
ちゃ、ちゃもにゃ……ちゃもにゃ？ちゃもにゃ！
Cha, chamonya... chamonya? Chamonya!
ちゃもにゃ？
Chamonya?
baby, i wanna be with you
oh baby baby, i wanna be with you
'cause you're my love, you're my shine, you're my dear
so trust me, trust me, trust me yeah!
i'm here, soba ni iru kara
I'm here because I'm right by your side
call me, boku ga iru kara
Call me because I am here for you
trust me, mou nani mo osorenaide
Trust me, don't be afraid of anything anymore
my dear, mienai ito de
My dear, connected by invisible threads
trust me, tsuna gatte iru kara
Trust me, because we are connected
tada kanji te ite, kono nukumori
Just feel this warmth
chanto kiko ete iru, kimi no kokoro no koe
I can hear your heart's voice clearly
chiisana fuan sae boku ga tsumi totte ageru
I will pluck away even your smallest anxieties
nando mo tsutaetai, kimi wa hitori janai
I want to tell you over and over, you're not alone
kawaru koto no nai ai wa kitto koko ni aru
An unchanging love is surely here
naite mireba ii, tay otte mireba ii
It's okay to cry, it's okay to lean on me
sono subete wo uke to meru to kimeta
I've decided to accept all of it
i'm here, doko ni ita tte
I'm here, no matter where you are
call me, hitotsu ni nareru
Call me, we can become one
trust me, kono omoi hodo kenai kara
Trust me, because these feelings won't unravel
my dear, kaka eta nimotsu
My dear, the baggage you're carrying
trust me, oroshite mireba ii
Trust me, you can put it down
sou kimi no tame ni boku ga irunda
Yes, I am here for your sake
dore hodo no kanashimi kimi wa kakushite ta no?
How much sorrow have you been hiding?
dore hodo no omoi wo mune ni tojikomete kita no?
How many feelings have you locked away in your chest?
itami to hiki kae ni teni ireta tsuyosa wo
The strength you gained in exchange for pain
itsuka yasashisa e kimi wa kaete yu keru hazu
You should be able to turn it into kindness someday
ubawareta te, kowa sareta te
Hands that were taken away, hands that were broken
daijina no wa kimi-rashiku iru koto
What's important is staying true to yourself
i'm here, tatoe sekai ga
I'm here, even if the world
call me, owaru to shite mo
Call me, were to come to an end
trust me, tsunagu te wo hanasanai kara
Trust me, because I won't let go of our joined hands
my dear, itsuwari no nai
My dear, with no falsehoods
trust me, mirai e aruki das ou
Trust me, let's walk out into the future
sou kimi no tame ni boku ga irunda
Yes, I am here for your sake
i'm here, soba ni iru kara
I'm here because I'm right by your side
call me, boku ga iru kara
Call me because I am here for you
trust me, mou nani mo osorenaide
Trust me, don't be afraid of anything anymore
my dear, mienai ito de
My dear, connected by invisible threads
trust me, tsuna gatte iru kara
Trust me, because we are connected
tada kanji te ite, kono nukumori
Just feel this warmth
itsu made mo soba ni iru, forever
I'll be by your side forever
nitsu matte mo hanarenai, never ever
We'll never ever be apart
kimi ga ireba, whatever you do
As long as you're here, whatever you do
nee boku ni oshiete, whatever you say
Hey, tell me whatever you say
tsurai koto areba subete nimo komi
If there are painful things, share them all with me
moshi sore de mo muri naraba, call me call me
If even then it's too much, call me, call me
you're my love, you're my shine, you're my dear
sekai teki ni mawashite mo, trust me
Even if the whole world turns against us, trust me
trust me, yei jeh eh
Trust me, yeah yeah eh
naite mireba ii, tay otte mireba ii
It's okay to cry, it's okay to lean on me
sono subete wo uke to meru to kimeta
I've decided to accept all of it
i'm here, doko ni ita tte
I'm here, no matter where you are
call me, hitotsu ni nareru
Call me, we can become one
I'm here, soba ni iru kara
I'm here, because I'm by your side
Call me, boku ga iru kara
Call me, because I'm here
Trust me, mou nani mo osorenaide
Trust me, don't be afraid of anything anymore
My dear, mienai ito de
My dear, with an invisible thread
Trust me, tsunagatte iru kara
Trust me, because we are connected
Tada kanjite ite, kono nukumori
Just feel this warmth
Chanto kikoete iru, kimi no kokoro no koe
I can hear it clearly, the voice of your heart
Chiisana fuan sae boku ga tsumitotte ageru
I will gather up even your small anxieties
Nando mo tsutaetai, kimi wa hitori ja nai
I want to tell you again and again, you are not alone
Kawaru koto no nai ai wa kitto koko ni aru
The love that never changes is surely here
Naite mireba ii, tayotte mireba ii
It's alright if you try crying, it's alright if you try relying on me
Sono subete wo uketomeru to kimeta
I have decided to accept all of it
I'm here, doko ni ita tte
I'm here, no matter where you are
Call me, hitotsu ni nareru
Call me, we can become one
Trust me, kono omoi hodokenai kara
Trust me, because I won't let go of these feelings
Trust me, baby
Naite mireba ii
It's alright if you try crying
Tayotte mireba ii
It's alright if you try relying on me
Sono subete wo uketomeru to kimeta
I have decided to accept all of it
I'm here, doko ni ita tte
I'm here, no matter where you are
Call me, hitotsu ni nareru
Call me, we can become one
Trust me, kono omoi hodokenai kara
Trust me, because I won't let go of these feelings
My dear, kakaeta nimotsu
My dear, the burden you are carrying
Trust me, oroshite mireba ii
Trust me, it's alright if you put it down
Sou kimi no tame ni boku ga iru n da
Yes, I am here for your sake
Dare hodo no kanashimi kimi wa kakushiteta no?
How much sadness were you hiding?
Dare hodo no omoi wo mune ni tojikomete kita no?
How much of your feelings did you keep locked in your chest?
Itami to hikikae ni te ni ireta tsuyosa wo
The strength you obtained in exchange for the pain
Itsuka yasashisa e kimi wa kaete yukeru hazu
Someday you should be able to turn it into kindness
Ubawareta tte, kowasareta tte
Even if it's taken away, even if it's broken
Daiji na no wa kimi-rashiku iru koto
What's important is to remain like yourself
I'm here, tatoe sekai ga
I'm here, even if the world
Call me, owaru to shite mo
Call me, were to end
Trust me, tsunagu te wo hanasanai kara
Trust me, because I won't let go of the hands we're holding
My dear, itsuwari no nai
My dear, with nothing false
Trust me, mirai e arukidasou
Trust me, let's walk towards the future
Sou kimi no tame ni boku ga iru n da
Yes, I am here for your sake
I'm here, soba ni iru kara
I'm here, because I'm by your side
Call me, boku ga iru kara
Call me, because I'm here
Trust me, mou nani mo osorenaide
Trust me, don't be afraid of anything anymore
My dear, mienai ito de
My dear, with an invisible thread
Trust me, tsunagatte iru kara
Trust me, because we are connected
Tada kanjite ite, kono nukumori
Just feel this warmth
Halo...? Anybody here?
Hello...? Anybody here?
Aku udah sering main game horror, tapi nggak tahu kenapa...
Okay, I have played enough horror games and I don't know why...
...ini kayak ngingetin aku sama sesuatu. Ini, suasananya seram.
...it reminds me of something similar. This feels so eerie.
Baca nggak, ya? Dibaca?
Should I read this? Maybe?
Nani ga mokuteki desuka
What is your purpose?
Nande irun desuka
Why are you here?
Kiretemasuka
Are you broken?
Okotemasuka
Are you angry?
Koko ni ite ii desuka
Is it okay to be here?
Modorimasu
I'll go back.
Kaerimashouka
Shall we return?
Modorouka
Shall we go back?
Nani sureba ii
What should I do?
Nanika tetsudaemasuka
Can I help you with anything?
Tekii wa arimasuka
Are there any enemies?
Nanimono desuka
What kind of person are you?
Doko ni imasuka
Where are you?
Chikaku ni imasuka
Are you nearby?
Detekite
Come out!
Apiru shite kudasai
Please make your presence known!
Moshi moshi
Hello, hello?
Loh, kok? Pintunya mirip sama pintu masuk tadi...
Huh? Wait, that door looks similar to the entrance door...
Jangan-jangan itu pintu keluar? Atau jebakan?
Could that be the exit? Or is it a trap?
Kalau ini game horror, coba teriak aja gitu?
Well, if this is a horror game, should I try to scream?
AAAAAHHH!!
Diam!
Quiet!
Eh?
Sousa kanashimi wo yasashisa ni
Yeah, turn sadness into kindness
Jibun rashisa wo chikara ni
With the strength of your own personality
Mayoinagarademo ii arukidashite
It's alright to keep walking even if you feel lost
Mou ikkai mou ikkai
Once more, once more
Dareka no kitai ni zutto kotae
Do you like being praised for always meeting
Homerareru no ga suki na no desuka?
Someone else's expectations?
Naritai jibun wo surikaetemo
Even if you swap out who you want to be
Egao wa itsudemo suteki desuka?
Is that smile always charming?
Hajimari dake yume mite okiru
Awakening after only dreaming of the beginning
Sono saki nara itsuka jibun no ude de
If there is something beyond that, one day it will be by your own hands
Souda daiji na mono wa itsumo katachi no nai mono dake
That's right, important things are always things without form
Te ni iretemo nakushitemo kizukanu mama
Whether you obtain them or lose them without even realizing it
Sousa kanashimi wo yasashisa ni
Yeah, turn sadness into kindness
ただあなただけ ひとつだけ
Just you, and only you,
この気持ちは ここにしかない
These feelings exist only here.
昨日も今日も 夢に出てきた
You appeared in my dreams yesterday and today,
あなたはしっかり 笑顔でいた
With a firm smile on your face.
少しだけ 手を繋いでみたら
When I tried holding your hand for a bit,
当たり前のように 握り返した
You naturally squeezed back.
もう一回
One more time!
二十歳、子供の説教だけ
Just a twenty-year-old child's lecture,
頭ごなしの説教だけ
Just a blind, preachy reprimand.
自分を信じられなくなって
Losing faith in myself,
傷つけながら すぐに尖って
Getting hurt and instantly turning sharp-edged.
新しい風が 味方に突きつけて
A new wind confronts our allies,
探していいんだいつか
It's okay to search for it someday,
青い鳥を
For the blue bird.
そうさ大事なものは いつも
Yes, what's truly important is always
形のないものだけ
Something without a tangible form.
手に入れても なくしても
Whether we gain it or lose it,
気づかぬまま
Without even realizing it.
そうさ 悲しみを 優しさに
Yes, transforming sorrow into kindness,
自分らしさを 力に
Turning our true selves into strength.
迷いながらでもいい 歩き出して
Even if you're lost, it's fine—start walking.
涙のあとは
After the tears,
なぜか吹切れた
Somehow things cleared up.
空に逃げるように自然のこと
Like escaping into the sky, so naturally.
涙のあとは なぜか吹切れた 空に逃げるように自然のこと
After the tears, somehow things cleared up, escaping into the sky so naturally.
壁は上がった だから大事なものは いつも 形のないものだけ
The wall rose up, so what's truly important is always something without form.
手に入れても なくしても 気づかぬまま
Whether we gain it or lose it, without even realizing it.
そうさ 悲しみを 優しさに 自分らしさを 力に
Yes, turning sorrow into kindness, our true selves into strength.
迷いながらでもいい 歩き出して
Even if you're lost, it's fine—start walking.
もう一回
One more time!
君ならきっとやれる 信じていて
You can definitely do it, keep believing.
もう一回
One more time!
小さな頃には 宝の地図が 頭の中に 浮かんでいた
When I was little, a treasure map was floating in my mind.
いつでも探した 奇跡の場所を 知らない誰かに 負けないように
Always searching for that miraculous place, so I wouldn't lose to someone I don't know.
今では埃だらけの毎日 いつかすべての ときに身をまかせるだけ
Now, my every day is covered in dust, someday just surrendering to the flow of time.
もしも世界が変わるのなら 何も知らない頃の私に
If this world is going to change, take me to the me who didn't know anything,
連れて行って 思い出が色褪せないように
So these memories won't fade away.
埃だらけの毎日に いつ日の光が
In these dusty days, someday the light...
すべてのときに見をまかせるだけ
Just surrendering to every moment.
ときに見をまかせるだけ
Just surrendering to the moment.
もしも世界が変わるのなら 何も知らない頃の私に
If this world is going to change, take me to the me who didn't know anything,
連れて行って 思い出が色褪せないように
So these memories won't fade away.
触れていて 思い出が色褪せないように
Keep touching them so these memories won't fade away.
広い宇宙の 数ある一つ
In this wide universe, one of many,
青い地球の 広い世界で
on the blue Earth's wide world,
小さな恋の 思いは届く
a small love's feelings will reach you,
小さな島の あなたのもとへ
to you on your small island.
あなたと出会い 時は流れる
Time has passed since I met you,
思いを込めた 手紙もふえる
letters filled with my feelings increase.
いつしか二人 互いに響く
Before we knew it, echoing between us,
時には激しく 時には切なく
sometimes intense, sometimes painful.
響くは遠く 遥か彼方へ
Echoing far, to the distant beyond,
やさしい歌は 世界を変える
a gentle song changes the world.
ほら あなたにとって 大事な人ほど
Look, the person most important to you
すぐそばにいるの
is right by your side.
ただ あなたにだけ 届いて欲しい
I just want it to reach only you,
響け恋の歌
echo, song of love.
ほら ほら ほら
Look, look, look,
響け 恋の歌
echo, song of love.
あなたは気づく 二人は歩く
You realize, the two of us walk
暗い道でも 日々照らす月
even on dark paths, the moon shines daily.
握りしめた手 離すことなく
Clasping hands, never letting go,
思いは強く 永遠誓う
feelings are strong, swearing for eternity.
永遠の淵 きっと僕は言う
At the edge of forever, I'm sure I'll say
思い変わらず 同じ言葉を
the same words, feelings unchanged.
それでも足りず 涙にかわり
Even still not enough, turning to tears,
喜びになり
turning into joy.
言葉にできず ただ抱きしめる
Unable to put into words, I just hold you close,
ただ抱きしめる
I just hold you close.
ほら あなたにとって 大事な人ほど
Look, the person most important to you
すぐそばにいるの
is right by your side.
ただ あなたにだけ 届いて欲しい
I just want it to reach only you,
響け恋の歌
echo, song of love.
ほら ほら ほら
Look, look, look,
響け 恋の歌
echo, song of love.
夢ならば 覚めないで
If it's a dream, don't wake up,
if it's a dream, don't wake up.
あなたと過ごした 時
The time I spent with you
永遠の星となる
becomes an everlasting star.
ほら あなたにとって 大事な人ほど
Look, the person most important to you
すぐそばにいるの
is right by your side.
ただ あなたにだけ 届いて欲しい
I just want it to reach only you,
響け恋の歌
echo, song of love.
ほら ほら ほら
Look, look, look,
響け 恋の歌
echo, song of love.
Kenapa semuanya terasa nyata banget?
Why does everything feel so real?
Apa aku nyata?
Am I real?
Apa orang lain bisa ngerasain keberadaanku?
Can others even feel my existence?
Apa ini yang namanya déjà vu?
Is this what déjà vu feels like?
All these memories mean the world to me.
Thank you for walking this journey with me.
Let's make more! :3
like! comments! share! subscribe! :)